SELDON T. TSELUNG

(646) 725-8476 ♦ New York, NY

stselung@gmail.com \$\ linkedin.com/in/seldontselung \$\ \\$\ github.com/SeldonTselung

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer seeking entry level front-end, back-end, full-stack or software engineering roles. With 5+ years of mechanical engineering experience, I am confident in my ability to communicate well, be a team player, pay attention to details, meet project deadlines, and deliver results.

EDUCATION

Certified, Software Engineering, The Grace Hopper Program at Fullstack Academy Master of Science, Mechanical Engineering, Rochester Institute of Technology Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering, Rochester Institute of Technology

February 2022 December 2015 May 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Postman, Firebase, Firestore, MongoDB, AWS EC2, Git, GitHub, CS Fundamentals, Data Structures and Algorithms

PROJECTS

NASA Launch App (github.com/SeldonTselung/NASA-Launch-App)

Present

A cloud deployed web app that combines NASA data with SpaceX API to build a space launch system. Users can schedule a launch to a habitable planet, abort a launch and view a history of launches. Designed schema using lucid-app, built front-end using HTML, JS, and React and managed states using React Hooks. Built back-end's non-relational db using Mongoose and MongoDB, built a RESTful API using MVC architecture, Node, Express and AXIOS, and finally deployed app using Docker and AWS's EC2.

OnlyFoods (github.com/2111-Patisserie/2111-OnlyFoods)

2022

A fully deployed social app created following Agile Workflow and Development principles. The app allows users to login and add/edit/share/post/bookmark recipes. Designed schema and wire-frames using draw.io, developed MVP, and used Github for VC purposes. Built front-end by using React Native, React Hooks for state management with Expo framework. Built back-end database using Firestore and authentication using Firebase.

The Greenhouse (github.com/2111-pellow/The-Green-House)

2022

A mock e-commerce website that features a product catalog for various types of plants, secured login experience, and persistent user sessions. The front-end was designed and built using HTML, CSS, JS, React and Redux, allowing users to browse, filter, sort, add to cart, view cart and check out. Built RESTful API using Node and Express, and built database using PostgreSQL.

EXPERIENCE

Full-time Student

June 2021 - Feb 2022

The Grace Hopper Program at Fullstack Academy

New York, NY

Mechanical Design Engineer

Jan 2019 - May 2021

Boyce Technologies Inc.

Long Island City, NY

- Lead design engineer for the Enhanced Emergency Booth Communication System Project, which successfully passed 100% of MTA's physical, thermal, vibration, and sealing specifications on the first attempt.
- Proactively achieved production deliverables through frequent communication with all team members, issuing 100+ engineering changes, and producing clear work instructions for machining, assembly and quality depts.
- Mentored a junior engineer and an intern by teaching them how to use AutoCad effectively.
- Successfully led a team for production field test at 6 MTA (Metropolitan Transportation Authority) stations using proper protocols and tools, thorough analyses and team work.
- Successfully tested and passed 3000 Spiro Wave Emergency ventilators for FDA approval in 3 months.

Mechanical Design Engineer

Apr 2016 - Oct 2018

Amphenol Aerospace

Sidney, NY

- Led the Next Generation composite connectors project by researching, designing, and developing the first samples of new prototypes.
- Managed and accelerated the launch of in-flight entertainment Bantam connectors by providing quick engineering support for marketing needs, drawings, and technical solutions.
- Successfully transitioned enhanced anti-decoupling Dualok Connectors from series I to II by issuing 100+ engineering changes that involved design, manufacturing processes and test procedures.

CERTIFICATES

Basic Project Management – Alliance for manufacturing and technology (April, 2018)

PUBLICATION

A 3D biomechanical model for analysis of upper jaw protrusion in Carassius Auratus, RIT Scholar Works, December 2015.